Md Muzahidul Islam

Dhaka, Bangladesh +8801744813601 mmsaddam@gmail.com <u>Linkedin</u> <u>Github</u> <u>Stackoverflow</u>

I am a professional iOS developer with 4.5 years of experience. Self motivated, enthusiastic, goal oriented and a team player. Remain calm, focused and motivated to resolve any problem. I love open source. Always try to follow the best practice and love to explore new technologies.

Skills

→ Mobile App: Swift, RxSwift, Objective C, Cocoa Touch, Sprite Kit

→ Web App: Laravel, Javascript, Node-Webkit

→ Data Store: SQLite, Core Data, Google Firebase

→ Tools: CocoaPods, Git, JIRA, Trello, Asana

Job Experience

Pathao Inc. — Software Engineer

September 2017 to Present

Pathao is the biggest ride sharing and online food delivery platform in Bangladesh. I started to develop the food delivery app from its scratch and also support the ride sharing app. Analyze the business requirements and incorporate into app. Working in MVVM-C design pattern and Reactive Swift. Implement deep linking, push notification and couple of analytics tools such crashlytics, fabric, clevertap, appsflyer.

East West Media Group, Bangladesh — *Software Engineer*

September 2016 - August 2017

Here I had worked in a Messenger application. Implemented user timeline where user can create new post, browse other's posts, react and comment on post. Contact management and made a drawing board. Experience in XMPP technology, WebRTC, Pushkit, Core Data. DB migration, image filtering.

Digi Tech Bangladesh Limited — *Software Engineer*

April 2015 - August 2016

Here I have worked in a couple of banking applications. I made Online Banking application for iOS. Developed a Cash Deposit Machine application using Node-Webkit for linux platform. Developed a blood donation social networking app.

RTC Hubs Limited, Bangladesh — *Junior Programmer*

January 2014 - May 2015

Started my engineering career here. Started learning iOS development. Made couple of in house iOS app using Objective-C. Familiar with UIKit, Sprite Kit, In-App Purchase, Core Animation and other iOS framework.

Project Experience

[Pathao] https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/pathao/id1201700952?mt=8

- → Features:
 - Ride sharing,
 - Online food and parcel delivery
- → Language: Swift
- → Technology: Swift, Reactive Programming, Socket Programming,
- → Architecture: MVVM-C, Clean Architecture
- → Tools: Firebase, JIRA, Git, Crashlytics, Fabric, Appsflyer

[GagaGugu] https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/gagagugu/id1228587989?ls=1&mt=8

- → Features:
 - Free text messaging
 - Video and Audio calling
 - Create new post, browse post, react and comment on post
- → Technology: Swift, XMPP, WebRTC, CoreData

[App Banking]

→ Features:

- Transfer balance to another account
- Pay utility bills
- Find ATM location and Branch location (google map integrated)
- Check transaction history
- → Technology: Swift, Audio jack reader

[Flow Game]

→ Features:

- A complete e-commerce iOS application
- Create, edit and update inventory(product) into shop
- Add inventory into cart and pay through card
- Audio jack smart card reader functionality implemented
- Prints transaction details on paper using micro printer
- → **Technology**: Swift, Micro printer SDK

[Bloodbond]

→ Features:

- Complete implementation of <u>Bloodbond</u> networking site
- Facebook login implemented
- Post blood request, browse blood requests
- User can see his blood donation cycle
- Firebase push notification implemented
- → Language: Swift

[Multi Shot Cam] https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/multi-shot-cam-takemultiple/id594437267?mt=8

- → Features:
 - Serial photo capturing
 - Editing and sharing
- → Language: Objective-C

[Battery Activity Monitor]

https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/battery-activitymonitor/id880047729?ls=1&mt=8

→ Features:

- Monitoring battery drain
- Power consuming by apps and show graphically
- Give warning if some app uses too much power
- → Language: Objective-C

[Dream Fixtures 2014] https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/dream-fixtures2014/id887820503?mt=8

- **→** Features:
 - Football world cup winner prediction and sharing the chart on social media.
- → Language: Swift

[Guess The Players] https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/guess-theplayers/id1109840109?ls=1&mt=8

- → Features:
 - Guess the celebrity player by seeing his pseudo image
 - Multi level game
- → Language: Swift

[iCHat] https://github.com/mmsaddam/iChat

- → Features:
 - Free Text messaging
 - Image sharing
- → Language: Swift
- → **DB**: Firebase

Education

B. Sc in Computer Science, 2014

Rajshahi University of Engineering & Technology